Guide to the Clyde Roark Hoey Papers, 1943-1954 RL.00556
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Clyde Roark Hoey papers
1943-1954
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hoey, Clyde Roark, 1877
RL.00556
100 Linear Feet 211 boxes; about 167,000 items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Hoey Papers were presented to Duke University in 1955 by his sons and daughter.
Biographical Note
Chronology
1877 Clyde Roark Hoey born, 11 December
1899 Studied law, University of North Carolina
1898-1902 Served in N. C. House of Representatives
1899 Admitted to North Carolina Bar
1900 Married Bessie Gardner
1902-1904 Served in N. C. Senate
1913-1919 Appointed Assistant United States District Attorney, Western North Carolina District
1919-1921 Declined re-nomination. Resumed law practice, 1921 Elected to 66th Congress to fill vacancy caused by resignation of Edwin Y. Webb.
1928 Democratic Presidential Elector-at-Large
1937-1941 Governor of North Carolina
1944-1954 United States Senator from North Carolina until his death on May 13, 1954
Committee Assignments
1945-1954 Agriculture and Forestry
1945-1946 District of Columbia
1947-1952 Expenditures in the Executive Departments
1949-1954 Finance
1953-1954 Government Operations
1945-1946 Immigration
1945-1946 Interstate Commerce
Collection Overview
The Clyde Roark Hoey Papers consist of office files created during Hoey's service in the United States Senate from 1944 through April, 1954. Correspondence, typed and printed material, clippings, and pictures provide a chronicle of Hoey's national political career as well as of American affairs during the early post-World War II period.
The Clyde Roark Hoey Papers consist of Hoey's senatorial files accumulated in his offices in Washington, D. C. and Shelby N. C. The papers cover the period from 1943 through April, 1954, but there are few items for 1943. The quantity of material is greater for the years toward the end of Hoey's career. The Hoey Papers are divided into two series: Correspondence and Subjects. For information on the structure of the collection consult the Series Description.
Incoming and outgoing correspondence with related clippings, printed material, and photographs predominates in both series. Constituent mail forms the largest category of correspondence, encompassing several types of letters and varying widely in significance and content. Many letters from constituents urge Hoey to support or oppose particular legislation, such as universal military training, grain exports to India, or tax measures. They range from the mass-produced form letter to the more detailed and analytical arguments of prominent businessmen, educators, and politicians in North Carolina. Other constituent mail relates to North Carolina projects and affairs such as power dams, defense plants, and appropriations to local interest groups. Still other constituent mail consists of requests for Hoey's assistance in obtaining employment or promotions, changing military status, obtaining visas, and similar personal matters, Routine correspondence involves requests for publications, general letters of commendation, or publicity about individual constituents,
Correspondence from all areas of the country concerns legislation or provides comment on world or domestic affairs in the postwar period. Colleagues in the Senate and members of the North Carolina congressional delegation are represented in the correspondence, but frequently they write only letters of transmittal or send personal greetings. A few letters involve the Hoey family. Most of these are exchanged between Senator Hoey and his son-in-law, Dan M, Paul. For some years personal and family papers are filed with H correspondence. For more information on individuals who corresponded with Hoey, consult the Partial List of Correspondents for 1949 in the Series Description.
The main part of the Subject Series is an alphabetical file containing correspondence and printed material about national and state affairs. Most of this correspondence is also constituent or pressure mail. Specific subjects in the Series are described in more detail in the Container listing. Speeches and miscellaneous items are included in the Subject Series.
A Note on Processing and Arrangement
Although some adjustments and consolidations were necessary, the Hoey Papers were organized and arranged according to the filing structure devised in the Senator's office. Correspondence from the offices in Washington and Shelby was merged, The year-by-year alphabetical arrangement was retained. In constructing the Subject Series, the categories originally entitled Legislation (filed often by subject and congressional session), Miscellaneous Legislation, and smaller categories such as Prisoners, Visas, Army, Navy, or specific North Carolina projects were consolidated to form one alphabetical sequence.
Certain Individual items, such as many requests for publications and arrangements for school tours, duplicates, and anniversary congratulations were discarded. Service academy applications and invitations were also removed. For the Army, Navy, and Veterans subject groups, samples of correspondence written by persons having surnames starting with the letter C were retained.
Partial List of Correspondents
Abernethy, Arthur Talmage
Abernethy, Charles Laban, Jr
Abernethy, R. O.*
Acheson, Dean (concerns nomination of George V. Allen; July 8)
Adams, Hoover (editor, Dunn Dispatch)*
Adams, Junius*
Adamson, C. F. (Wilkes Hosiery Mills)
Akers, John M (truck line)
Alexander, Kelly
Anderson, Mary (Chairman, National Commission on the Status of Women; Equal Rights Amendment and organizations opposing it; Feb. 5)
Andrews, Charles
Anthony, Graham*
Armstrong, Frank (N.C. Superior Court Judge)*
Ashford, G. T. (Liberty Manufacturing Company)
Atkins, J. Murray
Ayers, Nathan M. (President, Triangle Hosiery Company)
Bacon, James E. (on investment of risk capital)
Bailey, Edith Pou
Bailey, James Hinton Pou
Baker, J. E.*
Baldwin, Raymond E. (about Cannon Mills)
Barfield, Frances L (discrimination against women in government services, Sept. 22)
Barnes, Wiley G.
Beckerath, Herbert von (Duke University)
Benoit, Henry B. (President, Charlotte Laundry Association)*
Binder, Norma VanLandingham
Black, Bedford
Blake, William Rea (President, National Cotton Council of U. S. A )
Blythe, LeGette
Boise, Vance (State Highway Commission)
Bolton, Neil
Banner, Herbert C.
Bost, Tom
Bowick, H. A (President, Columbus [Ga.] Typographical Union, no. 220)
Brandis, Henry, Jr (Dean, University of North Carolina Law School)
Branson, Russell (American Friends Services Committee)
Braxton, H. Gait*
Bridges, Henry
Brimley, Ralph (See also Subject Series: Labor--Ralph Brimley)*
Brower, A S.
Brown, Mrs. L. E (President, Woman's Christian Temperance Union)
Brown, Walter M (President, Brown's Hosiery Mills, Burlington)
Buchanan, Corsey C.
Bulwinkle, A L
Burwell, Lewis
Butler, A L. (Arista Mills, Winston-Salem, N. C.)
Butler, Rev. I. B. National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, Wilson, N. C.)
Byrd, Harry Flood*
Campbell, Leslie H.*
Cannon, Charles A.*
Carlyle, F. Ertel
Carmichael, William D.
Carpenter, J. Harvey
Carraway, Gertrude
Carruthers, Marvin S.
Chatham, Thurmond
Cheek, Roma S.
Chelf, Frank L. (Methodist Church)
Cherry, J. Robert, Jr
Clark, David
Clemens, Cyril (postcard)
Clement, Hunt
Coates, Albert
Cobb, Beatrice
Cockrell, Ewing
Colclough, George D. (Burlington Chamber of Commerce)
Collier, Robert A.
Cone, Benjamin
Cone, Bonnie E.*
Cone, Ceasar*
Cone, Herman
Cook, William D.
Cooley, Harold D.
Cooper, Thomas F.
Couch, William T.
Coxe, Fred J.
Craige, Archibald
Craven, J. Braxton*
Crew, Winfield
Cross, Hathaway
Crouch, Kenneth E (The Bedford [Va.] Democrat)*
Cuthbertson, W. R. (Hanker)
Dalton, Robert I., Jr.
Daniels, Harry*
Daniels, Jonathan
Davis, Durham (American Legion)
Davis, Herbert L.
Davis, Dr. James W. (about black hospital in Statesville, N. C.)
Davis, Thomas W.
Deane, Charles B.
Deegan, Elizabeth
DeMille, Cecil B.
Dennis, Henry A. (Editor, Henderson Daily Dispatch)
Dickson, Rush S. (American Yarn and Processing Company)
Dillard, Rev, E. A. (of Hebron Colony, Inc., residential clinic for alcoholics)
Dixon, Frank M
Dixon, Richard D.
Disher, Harry L.
Dougherty, B. B. (President, Appalachian State Teachers' College)
Doughton, Robert L.
Dowd, Edward (Charlotte News)
Durham, Carl*
Eagles, J. C.
Easley, Dr. Eleanor B.
Edelman, John W. (of Textile Workers' Union of America)
Edens, A. Hollis
Edwards, Alonzo C. (N. C, General Assembly)
Edwards, Ethel Perkins (Executive Secretary, N.C. Education Association)
Edwards, Ralph
Ehringhaus, J. C. B.
Elias, Don S. (Asheville Citizen-Times)
Elliott, P. L. (Gardner-Webb College)
Elmore, Sam
Ervin, Paul R.
Ervin, Sam J., Jr.*
Erwin, Clyde A. (N. C. Superintendent of Public Instruction)*
Erwin, J. Ernest (on communism; item of Mar, 2 includes printed material, the Textile Workers' Voice, about communists in the textile industry)
Etheridge, R. Bruce
Eubanks, Clyde
Eure, Thad*
Evans, Clyde M.
Evans, E. Hervey
Evans, May Thompson (See also Subject Series)
Fain, J. R.
Falls, Watson
Farnell, Newton
Fechtig, F. H.*
Ferebee, Percy B.
Ferguson, Garland S. (Federal Trade Commissioner)*
Ferrell, John A.
Fesperman, Tom (Charlotte News)
Fetner, Vida M.
Few, Benjamin F.
Few, Mrs. William Preston
Ficklen, William M.
Finch, Ronald E.
Fink, C. A. (President, N. C. State Federation of Labor)
Flack, Charles Z.
Flanders, Ralph E.
Fleishman, Maurice
Fletcher, A, J. (President, Capital Broadcasting Co.)
Flincham, Rev, Claude Edwin
Forbus, Sample B.
Fountain, L, H.*
Frazier, Rawls
Frear, J. Allen (U.S. Senate)
Freeman, Mrs. Ozell K.
Froneberger, Robert Brevard*
Fulbright, J. William
Gaffney, J. L.
Galvin, Hoyt
Ganderson, Harry
Gann, J. R. (hosiery mill)
Gant, Roger (Glen Raven Cotton Mills)
Gardner, O. Max *
Gardner, Ralph W.
Garinger, Elmer H.
Geer, William M.
Geoghegan, George P.*
Gettys, Claude
Gillette, Guy M. (Equal Rights Amendment, Jan. 10)
Gilliam, L. S., Jr.
Gillin, John
Glascow, Thomas
Gobbel, James T.*
Golden, Harry L.*
Goodwin, William J.
Graham, Grover C. (Methodist minister)
Grant, J. Marse
Gravely, Lee L.
Graves, Louis*
Gray, Gordon*
Grayson, Alda (observations on communist takeover in China, June 20)
Greene, E. C.*
Griffin, Lloyd
Grigg,-Horace
Gross, Paul
Grover, Wayne C.
Guion, W. B. Rodman *
Gurney, Robert J.
Hackney, Thomas J.
Hale, Albert S., Jr.
Hamilton, James G. DeRoulhac, Jr.
Hamilton, Luther (judge)
Hampton, Wade B.
Hancock, Frank W., Jr.
Hanes, Robert M, (Wachovia)
Hanner, John C,
Harden, John
Harding, Harry P. (educator)
Harkins, Thomas J.
Harlick, Wilson
Harrelson, Col. J. W.
Harrill, Bryan
Harrington, William
Harris, James J.
Harris, R. L.
Harry, Charles F.
Hatch, William T.
Hayden, Carl
Hayes, Leonidas B. (minister)
Haynes, Caleb H.
Haynes, Frank K.
Heartt, Leo D.
Henderson, David E.
Henderson, Thomas
Hershey, Lewis B.
Hester, John
Hicks, Randall J.
Hicks, Sterling L.
Hill, L. W.
Hill, Landon
Hill, Lister
Hilliard, J. A.
Hines, Charles A.
Hodges, Luther H.*
Hoffman, Paul G.
Hogan, George
Holt, Raymond H.
Hood, Eugene A. (Cone Mills)
Hood, Gurney P.
Horne, Joshua Lawrence*
Hubbell, Jay B.
Huggins, Rev. M. A.
Hunter, Rev. Coyte
Hutchins, Wesley
Hutto, Jasper C.
Hux Leonidas
Ingram, Robert L.
Ivie, Allan D., Jr.
Jackson, Frank L.
Johnson, Charles M.
Johnson, Leroy
Joiner, Arnold Wayne
Jones, Frank
Jones, G. Lyle
Jordan, Charles E.
Jordan, John Y., Jr.
Kanipe, J. Edward
Kelly, David L.
Kempton, George B.
Kendall, Henry E.
Kennedy, Horace
Kerr, John H.
Kerr, Robert S.
Kitchin, Thurman
Kizziah, William D.*
Koonts, Henry V.
Kuykendall, Edward P.
Lambeth, J. Walter
LaMotte, Louis C.
Lane, Thomas Guy, Jr.
Lang, John A., Jr.
Lassiter, William C.
Laughinghouse, Charles O'Hagan
Laughridge, Russell G.
Lea Clarence F.
Leak, James W.
Lin, Margaret Hie Ding
Lindley, J. Van
Lindsay, David
Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr.
Long, W. Lunsford*
Lowry, Herbert
Lupton, D. Warren
MacClamroch, James G. W.
MacRae, Donald C. (judge)
Maggs, Douglas B.
Mahler, Fred D.
Malone, Edwin H.
McAfee, Hoyt*
McCarran, Patrick A.
McCorkle, George
McCoy, Joseph B.
McCrary, Frank L.
McCrary, J. Frank
McGirt, W. A., Jr.
McGrath, J. Howard
McKay, Woodrow
McLesn, Dickson
McMullen, Harry*
McPherson, Holt*
McSwain, Peyton*
Menzies, Donald S.'
Mitchell, Hugh G.
Mooneyham, Oscar J.
Moore, J. Tracy
Moore, Louis
Moore, Odus L.
Morgan, C. Gerald
Morgan, Lucy (Penland School)
Morrison, Fred W.
Morton, Hugh M.
Moss, John H.
Mull, Clarence
Mundt, Karl E.
National Association of Wool Manufacturers
National Parks Association
Neaves, W. Avery
Neilson, George D.
Neville, Everette W.
Newmeyer, Arthur G.
Newton, Adrian J.
Noell, Hugh E.
Nolan, Clyde (Democratic Party)
Norris, Nell P.
Olive, Hubert B.
Padgitt, Bright Wilson
Page, Reid A.
Park, John A.
Park, John A.
Parker, Oscar L.
Parker, Roy
Parrott, Marion A.
Parsons, Catherine
Pease, J. Norman*
Peck, Lewis B.
Peele, Herbert
Pell, Allison H.*
Poe, Clarence*
Poole, J. Hawley
Pope Seth S.
Powell, Alice
Powell, Floyd
Powell, Rex G.
Price, Ralph C.
Proctor, John C.
Putnam, Robert J.
Quinn, A. B.
Radcliffe, George L.
Radt, Dick
Ragan, Caldwell
Ramsey, D. Hiden
Ramsey, Kerr Craige
Rankin, Carl
Rankin, Edward L.
Rankin, William W., Jr.
Ray, Frank D.
Reinhardt, J. Robert
Reynolds, Charles H.
Richards, Thomas B.
Ricks, William B.
Riddle, Harry L.
Riley, Jack (News and Observer editor)
Riser, L. Arnold
Ritch, Marvin Lee
Rives, E. Earl
Roberts, Coleman W.
Robertson, Reuben B.
Robinson, John D.
Rochelle, Zalph
Rodgers, Eric W.
Rogers, Carroll
Roister, John P.
Ross, George R.
Royall, Kenneth C.
Rucker, Pierce*
Rudisill, Justus G.
Ruffin, Thomas W.
Ruffin, William H.
Russell, Richard B.
Saleeby, A. S.*
Sample, Harry
Sanford, Terry*
Saunders, Patrick H.
Schenck, Jean W.
Scoggin, Hill
Scott, John A.
Scott, W. Kerr
Seifert, C. A.
Sellers, Tommy
Sentelle, John E.*
Shannonhouse, Norma
Sharp, Susie
Shaw, R. Flake
Shepard, Norman C.
Shoemaker Donald
Shuford, Adrian L.
Shuford, Forrest H.
Shuford, George
Simmons, Arthur
Simms, Robert N.
Sinclair, David
Smith, Alvin
Smith, Arthur Clarendon
Smith, Furman
Smith, Julius C.
Smith, Louis H.
Snow, Edgar N.
Sparkman, John
Spence, H. E.
Spengler, Joseph D.
Spivak, Lawrence E.
Stacy, Walter P.
Steinkraus, Herman W.
Stockton, Richard G.
Stone, Charles H.
Stroock, Sylvan I.
Suttle, Margaret
Sutton, Fred
Tanner, Kenneth S.
Tate, Sarah Wilson
Taylor, Herbert B.
Taylor, Hoyt Patrick
Taylor, James T. (NCCU)*
Taylor, Katherine
Teague, Samuel F.
Teal, J. Paul, Jr.
Teu, Sanfjord B. II*
Thigpen, Richard E.
Thomas, Elmer
Thomas, Ernest F.
Thomas, James H.
Thomas, John G.
Thomas, Woodrow W.
Thompson, Robert L.
Tillett, Charles A.*
Townsend, Folger L.
Trotter, Ben C.
Turberville, Frank B., Jr.
Turner, Thomas
Tuttle, Lee F.
Umstead, William B.*
Unger Sidney E,
Uzzeli, George R.
Uzzell, Thomas A.*
Valentine, Itimous
Vanlandingham, H. C.
Veach, John B.
Vick, Opal C.
Vines, John H.
Vogel, Paul W.
Vosburgh, Ed,
Wadden, Thomas A., Jr.
Wallace, Robert M.
Walser, Don A.
Ward, Mrs. Vernon A.
Ward, Philip C.
Warren, Abel
Warren, Addison
Warren, Ernest R.
Warren, Lindsay C.*
Warren, Thomas D.
Watkins, Arthur V.
Waynick, Capus*
Weathers, Lee B.*
Webb, Edwin Y., Jr.
Webb, James E.
Weeks, Cameron S.
Wells, John
Whicker, Joseph H., Sr.
Whisnant, Joseph C.
Whitaker, Bruce
White, E. L. (mayor of Wilmington, N.C.)
White, Jesse A.
White, John P.
White, Julian J.
Whitener, Basil L.
Whitfield, J. Vivian
Whitlock, Paul C.
Wilbur, Gorton T. H.
Willetts, Frederick
WIlliams, Robert R.
Williamson, W. Bill, Sr.
Wilson, Fred C.
Wilson, Louis Round
Winborne, J. Wallace
Winchell, Walter
Wohl, Harry
Woltz, Howard O., Jr.
Womble, B. S.
Woods, R. H.
Woosley, Oscar V.
Wright, Isaac C.
Yandle, Parks A.*
Yarbrough, Ernest
Younce, George A.
Young, Richard L., Jr.
Yount, Hubert M,
Zimmerman, Calvin*
Governors -- North Carolina; North Carolina -- Politics and government; Legislators -- Correspondence; Legislators -- United States; United States -- Politics and government -- 1945-1953; North Carolina -- Cleveland County -- Shelby; Pensions, Military -- Law and legislation -- United States; Taxation -- Law and legislation -- United States; Draft -- Law and legislation -- United States; Education -- Law and legislation -- United States; Agricultural laws and legislation -- United States; Hoey, Clyde Roark, 1877
- Correspondence, 1943-1954
  - 1943-1944 (Box 1)
    - A - C (Aug.) (Box 1)
    - C (Sept.)- G (Box 2)
    - H - M (Aug.) (Box 3)
    - M (Sept.)- S (Aug.) (Box 4)
    - S (Sept.)- Z (Box 5)
  - 1945
    - A - B (Aug.) (Box 5)
    - B (Sept.)- D (Aug.) (Box 6)
    - D (Sept.)- H (Aug.) (Box 7)
    - H (Sept.)- L (Aug.) (Box 8)
    - L (Sept.)- R (Aug.) (Box 9)
    - R (Sept.)- V (Box 10)
    - W - Z (Box 11)
  - 1946
    - A (Aug.)- B (Nov.)Note: Correspondence for this year begins in summer. (Box 11)
    - B (Nov.)- G (Box 12)
    - H (Aug.)- Mc (Box 13)
    - M - S (Oct.) (Box 14)
    - S (Nov.)- Z (Box 15)
  - 1947
    - A (Jan.- Sept.) (Box 15)
    - A (Oct.)- B (June) (Box 16)
    - B (July)- C (Mar.) (Box 17)
    - C (Apr.- Dec.) (Box 18)
    - D - E (Box 19)
    - F - G (Sept.) (Box 20)
    - G (Oct.)- H (July) (Box 21)
  - 1947 (Box 22)
    - H (July)- J (Dec.) (Box 22)
    - K - L (Box 23)
    - Mc - M (July) (Box 24)
    - M (July)- P (Apr.) (Box 25)
    - P (May)- R (Oct.) (Box 26)
    - R (Oct.)- S (Sept.) (Box 27)
    - S (Sept.)- T (Sept.) (Box 28)
    - T (Oct.)- W (Oct.) (Box 29)
    - W (Oct.)- Z (Box 30)
  - 1948
    - A (Box 30)
    - B (Jan.- Sept.) (Box 31)
    - B (Aug.)- C (Aug.) (Box 32)
    - C (Aug.)- D (Box 33)
    - E - F (Box 34)
    - G - H (Mar.) (Box 35)
    - H (Mar.- Dec.) (Box 36)
    - H (Dec.) (Box 37)
    - Hoey (Personal) (Box 37)
    - I - K (June) (Box 37)
    - K (June)- Mc (Mar.) (Box 38)
    - Mc (Mar.)- M (Sept.) (Box 39)
    - M (Sept.)- P (Apr.) (Box 40)
    - P (Apr.)- R (Mar.) (Box 41)
    - R (Apr.)- S (Mar.) (Box 42)
    - S (Mar.)- T (Feb.) (Box 43)
    - T (Feb.)- W (May) (Box 44)
    - W (May)- Z (Box 45)
  - 1949
    - A (Jan.- Sept.) (Box 45)
    - 1949. A (Oct.)- B (June) (Box 46)
    - B (June- Dec.) (Box 47)
    - C (Jan.- July) (Box 48)
    - C (Aug.)- D (Apr.) (Box 49)
    - D (May)- E (Aug.) (Box 5O)
    - E (Sept.)- G (Feb.) (Box 51)
    - G (Mar.)- H (Jan.) (Box 52)
    - H (Oct.- Aug.) (Box 53)
    - H (Aug.)- J (Mar.) (Box 54)
    - J (Apr.)- K (Box 55)
    - L - Mc (Mar.) (Box 56)
    - Mc (Apr.)- M (May) (Box 57)
    - M (June)- N (Box 58)
    - 0 - P (Aug.) (Box 59)
    - P (Sept.)- R (June) (Box 60)
    - R (July)- S (Apr.) (Box 61)
    - S (May- Sept.) (Box 62)
    - S (Oct.)- T (July) (Box 63)
    - T (Aug.)- W (Apr.) (Box 64)
    - W (May- Dec.) (Box 65)
    - W (names) - Z (Box 66)
  - 1950
    - A (Jan.- July) (Box 66)
    - A (July)- B (Mar.) (Box 67)
    - B (Apr.- Oct.) (Box 68)
    - B (Sept.)- C (Apr.) (Box 69)
    - C (May- Nov.) (Box 70)
  - 1950 (Box 71)
    - C (Nov.)- D (Box 71)
    - E - F (July) (Box 72)
    - F (Aug.)- G (July) (Box 73)
    - G (Aug.)- H (Apr.) (Box 74)
    - H (Apr.- Sept.) (Box 75)
    - H (Oct.)- J (Box 76)
    - K (Jan.)- L (Sept.) (Box 77)
    - L (Oct.)- M (Feb.) (Box 78)
    - M (Feb.- Dec.) (Box 79)
    - N - P (Oct.) (Box 80)
    - P (Nov.)- S (Feb.) (Box 81)
    - S (Mar.- Sept.) (Box 82)
    - S (Sept.)- T (Box 83)
    - U - W (Aug.) (Box 84)
    - W (Aug.)- Z (Box 85)
  - 1951
    - A (Jan.- May) (Box 85)
    - A (June)- B (Apr.) (Box 86)
    - B (May- Oct.) (Box 87)
    - B (Nov.)- C (June) (Box 88)
    - C (June)- D (June) (Box 89)
    - D (June)- F (Feb.) (Box 90)
    - F (Mar.)- G (May) (Box 91)
    - G (June)- H (May) (Box 92)
    - H (Apr.- Nov.) (Box 93)
    - H (Nov.)- K (Mar.) (Box 94)
    - K (Apr.)- L (Box 95)
  - 1951 (Box 96)
    - Mc - M (Apr.) (Box 96)
    - M (Apr.)- N (Box 97)
    - O - Q (Box 98)
    - R (Box 99)
    - S (Jan.- June) (Box 100)
    - S (June)- T (May) (Box 101)
    - T (June)- W (Mar.) (Box 102)
    - W (Mar.- Dec.) (Box 103)
    - X - Z (Box 104)
  - 1952
    - A - B (Mar.) (Box 104)
    - B (Mar.- Dec.) (Box 105)
    - C (Jan.- Oct.) (Box 106)
    - C (Oct.)- F (Feb.) (Box 107)
    - F (Mar.)- G (June) (Box 108)
    - G (June)- H (July) (Box 109)
    - H (Aug.)- K (Apr.) (Box 110)
    - K (May)- Mc (Mar.) (Box 111)
    - Mc (Mar.)- M (Box 112)
    - N - P (Sept.) (Box 113)
    - P (Oct.)- S (Jan.) (Box 114)
    - S (Feb.- Sept.) (Box 115)
    - S (Oct.)- V (Box 116)
    - W (Jan.- Dec.) (Box 117)
    - W (Dec.)- Z (Box 118)
  - 1953
    - A - B (Feb.) (Box 118)
    - B (Mar.- Dec.) (Box 119)
    - 1953. C (Jan.- Nov.) (Box 120)
    - C (Nov.)- F (Apr.) (Box 121)
    - F (Apr.)- H (Mar.) (Box 122)
    - H (Mar.)- J (Box 123)
    - K - Mc (May) (Box 124)
    - Mc (June)- M (Box 125)
    - N - R (Mar.) (Box 126)
    - R (Apr.)- S (Nov.) (Box 127)
    - S (Nov.)- W (Apr.) (Box 128)
    - W (May)- Z (Box 129)
  - 1954
    - A - B (Mar.)Note: Correspondence for this year stops in March (Box 129)
    - C (Jan.)- G (Mar.) (Box 130)
    - H (Jan.)- Mc (Mar.) (Box 131)
    - M (Jan.)- S (Mar.) (Box 132)
    - T - Z (Box 133)
- Subjects ca. 1943-1954
  - Main Sequence
    - Acheson, Dean (letters about) (Box 133)
    - Agricultural Adjustment Act, 1947-1948 (Box 133)
      Scope and Contents note
      Chiefly soil conservation
    - Agricultural Adjustment Act. 1949-1950 (Box 133)
      Potatoes
    - Agricultural Conservation Association, 1945 (Box 133)
      Salaries
    - Agricultural Appropriation Bill, 1951-1952 (Box 134)
      Applications for loans to finance generating plants
    - Agriculture Committee,1947, 1951-1952 (Box 134)
      Capper farm bill (agricultural marketing); Commodity Credit Corporation; report on grain storage, Camp Crowder, Mo.
    - Air Force Academy, 1951, 1954 (Box 134)
      Proposals to establish academy in Charlotte and Kitty Hawk, N. C.
    - Alaska Statehood, 1949-1953 (Box 134)
      See also Hawaii Statehood, 1954
    - Alcoholic Beverage Advertising, 1948, 1950 (Box 134)
    - Appointments
      Letters of recommendation or support from Hoey or constituents for various individuals as follows:
      - U. S. District Attorney in Middle District N. C., 1945-1946 (Box 134)
      - Assistant Attorney General of U. S. T. Lamar Caudle, 1945 (Box 134)
      - U. S. Supreme Court Judge John J. Parker, 1945 (Box 134)
      - Loan Administrator Frank W. Hancock, 1945 (Box 134)
      - Collector of the Port of Wilmington - various individuals, 1945-1946, 2 folders (Box 135)
      - Chairman, Tennessee Valley Authority, Gordon Clapp, 1947 (Box 135)
      - U. S. Judge, Western District N. C. Wilson Warlick, 1948, 2 folders (Box 135)
      - Assistant Secretary of Labor May Thompson Evans, 1948 (Box 135)
      - U. S. Deputy Marshall,1949 (Box 135)
      - U. S. Deputy Marshall, N. C. Districts,1949 (Box 136)
      - Member, Federal Power Commission Leland Olds, 1949, 2 folders (Box 136)
      - Member, Federal Trade Commission, 1949 John Carson (Box 136)
      - District Attorney of Western N. C. District, 1949-1950, Thomas Uzzell, 2 folders (Box 136)
      - Deputy U. S. Marshall for Western District, N. C., 1950-1951 (Box 136)
    - Appropriations ca. 1948-1953, 4 folders (Box 137)
      Correspondence concerning an assortment of appropriation requests, such as vocational education, public health, agricultural programs, etc. See also Budget and Power Dams, Appropriations.
    - Armed Forces Merger, 1946-1947 (Box 137)
    - Army, 1947-1950, 2 folders (Box 137)